JACK WOOD-PEARCE

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

+44 (0)7746223593 Frome, Somerset, jackwoodpearce@gmail.com A creative, dedicated engineer focussed on frontend development primarily in Typescript and React. With experience of working in-house and on agency projects, I enjoy collaborating within a team but can work independently to tight deadlines. I bring my background as an engineering manager to facilitate efficient code practices such as peer reviews and I am always working to develop my knowledge and interrogate my practice.

Favourite tools: JavaScript ES6, React, HTML 5, CSS, Sass

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer - Agency side

Digital Wonderlab, Bradford on Avon - January 2020 - Present

Lead frontend engineer working in close collaboration with the backend team and the designers to create responsive solutions across a variety of platforms for clients with a charitable or ethical interest. I have a strong understanding of GIT, with peer reviews, agile/scrum all forming an important part of my practice as a developer. Projects include:

Lonely Not Alone

In my role as the lead front end developer on this project I worked alongside the designers to build multiple proof of concepts, pushing the design from 2D to a 3D interactive design which exceeded the customer's expectations. I introduced and implemented three.JS library to the company, to realise this interactive night sky for children to share stories about loneliness.

https://lonelynotalone.org/

JavaScript ES6, webpack, three.js, tween.js, SASS

Alliance City

I independently built the complete front end for this gamified marketing training platform. The design used a fictional city based in the future to add a narrative around an online marketing course.

https://alliancecity.wndrtest.com/

(for site access please email me directly)

C# Blazor Web frontend framework, C#, JQuery, Bootstrap, component CSS, JavaScript ES6

United First Partners

This project involved me picking up Blazor, a framework which was new to me and introducing it to the company. I was the lead front end developer, building the front end myself in collaboration with the designers and backend team. Site features: data caching to remove loading screens and infinite scroll loading on main page. Challenges: 3 separate user databases and separate pricing options spread over 3 continents into a single frontend.

TEST SITE: https://ufp.ojotest.com/

https://www.utdfirst.com/

(for site access please email me directly)

Tech: C# Blazor, C#, Bootstrap, SASS

Great Western Union

As the lead front end developer, myself and the design team created a more customer centric website, highlighting finance offerings for its existing and new members. This included building a more sales orientated web presence, re-developing its existing online lending and membership offering and streamlining processes through a new CRM and integrated member area.

https://greatwesterncu.org/

Tech: C# Razor pages, Html5, Bootstrap, JQuery, CSS

Full Stack Developer - In House

Lovehoney, Bath - June 2018 - January 2020

Initially working on the subscriptions project creating a modified checkout which communicated with the backend. Consisted of a new frontend management system, landing page, checkout and integration with existing and new backend systems.

https://web.archive.org/web/20191228201403/https://www.lovehoney.co.uk/

Tech: React, TypeScript, Sass, ColdFusion and newly created APIs.

Worked as part of a team to integrate a new Klarna payment system into the main checkout working with **third party APIs** and integrating **secure iframes** into the checkout. The checkout processes over £120m/y in transactions though 9 sites across the world, so great care was made to maintain the user experience and performance.

Design Engineer

Etavoni, Radstock - Nov 2018 - Feb 2018

Engineering/Project Manager/Design Engineer

Armadillo Engineering, Malmesbury - Sept 2010 - Nov 2018

Principle Design Engineer responsible for all CAD development, prototyping and design of items manufactured by the company. And Engineering Manager; introduced, managed and achieved an ISO 900 I UKAS accredited quality management system. Including the development and integration of a new internal management system.

Design Assurance - Lloyds Interface Management

VT Shipbuilding- Aircraft Carrier Alliance, CVF project, Sept 07 - Sept 10

EDUCATION

Full-stack, intensive web development course.

Mayden Academy, Bath Feb 2018 to June 2018

Subjects covered on the course include: RESTful APIs in express and node.js, ES5 and ES6 JavaScript, PHP,Task runners such as Gulp and Brew, Creating new projects and adding features and debugging existing projects, DRY & SOLID principles and OOP, GIT and GitHub, HTML5 and CSS, MySQL and MongoDB, PWAs, cyber security, Backend frameworks such as PHP Zend, package managers (i.e., NPM)

More projects and challenges available to view on Github: github.com/C0deJack

B.Eng Hons Yacht & Powercraft Design

Southampton Solent University 2004 – 2007

References available upon request